Guide to Montana Public Service Commission, Utilities Division records 1913-1986
Montana Historical Society
Montana Public Service Commission, Utilities Division records
1913-1986
Montana Historical Society Archives
RS 297
Montana Public Service Commission. Utilities Division
31.5 linear feet of shelf space
These records consist primarily of annual reports (1914-1986) made by electric utility companies, gas companies, heating utility companies, water companies, telegraph companies, telephone companies, and pipeline companies to the Montana Public Service Commission. There are also accident reports (1957-1966) for electric and gas utilities.
The Montana Board of Railroad Commissioners was established by the Montana legislature in 1907. In 1913 the Board of Railroad Commissioners was made ex officio the newly created Montana Public Service Commission. As such, it was given the authority to regulate a variety of public utilities. In 1971 the Montana Board of Railroad Commissioners was abolished and its work was taken over directly by the Public Service Commission.
These records consist predominantly of annual reports (1914-1986) made by electric utility companies, gas companies, heating utility companies, water companies, telegraph companies, telephone companies, and pipeline companies to the Montana Public Service Commission. The reports include a vast amount of data on the history, financing, corporate ownership, physical plants, and production. Many of the reports are accompanied by rate schedules and regulations. Some of the reports are copies of the reports made to the Federal Power Commission and do not directly reflect their Montana operations.
In addition there are accident reports (1957-1966) for electric, gas, and telephone utilities; appraisal reports (1919-1927) for several electric utilities; and other reports (1922-1953) for several water companies.
The collection is arranged by subgroup and then by series.
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Electric utilities--Montana.; Gas companies--Montana.; Pipelines--Montana.; Public utilities--Montana.; Telegraph--Montana.; Telephone companies--Montana.; Water utilities--Montana.
Montana--Commerce.
Montana; Public Utilities
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Electric Power Companies, 1913-1969
  - Annual Reports
    - Anaconda Copper Mining Company Electric Light Department, 1929-1936 (Box-folder 1 / 1-2)
    - Ashland Light and Power Company (sold to Tongue River Electric Cooperative), 1937-1948 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
    - Black Hills Power and Light Company (copy of report to Federal Power Commission; served Belle Creek Oil Field, Montana), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
    - Bonneville Power Administration (copy of report to Federal Power Commission), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
    - Broadus Power Company (sold to Tongue River Electric Cooperative), 1948-1950 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
    - Circle Municipal Light Plant (sold to Rural Electric Administration), 1930-1946 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
    - City Light Company (Winnett), 1925-1945 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
    - City Light and Power Company (Grass Range; formerly Grass Range Milling Company; sold to Rural Electric Administration), 1932-1947 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
    - Cooke Light and Power Company (sold to Shoshone River Power, Inc.), 1944-1955 (Box-folder 1 / 10)
    - Cut Bank Electric Light and Power Company (sold to Great Northern Utilities Company), 1923-1927 (Box-folder 1 / 11)
    - Deer Lodge Electric Company (rate schedule only), 1923 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
    - Ekalaka Light and Power Company, 1931-1950 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
    - Eureka Electric Company (previously P. L. Howe Lumber Mills; name later changed to Tobacco River Power Company), 1925-1926 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
    - Gardiner Electric Light and Water Company (sold to Montana Power Company), 1922-1946 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
    - Grass Range Milling Company (becomes City Light and Power Company), 1922-1932 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
    - Great Falls Power Company (owned by Montana Power Company), 1914 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
    - Great Northern Utilities Company (Blackfoot, Browning, Cut Bank, Glacier Park, Kevin, Oilmont, Shelby, Sunburst, Sweetgrass; later some operations sold to cooperatives), 1923-1946 (Box-folder 1 / 17-22)
    - Helming Brothers (Wisdom), 1943-1944 (Box-folder 1 / 23)
    - O. B. Hoven Electric Light and Power Company (Antelope; sold to Montana-Dakota Utilities Company), 1920 (Box-folder 1 / 24)
    - P. L. Howe Lumber Mills (Eureka; sold to Eureka Electric Company), 1922 (Box-folder 1 / 25)
    - V. H. Hungerford (Oilmont; sold to Great Northern Utilities Company), 1927-1928 (Box-folder 1 / 26)
    - Ingomar Milling Company / Ingomar Light and Power Company, 1924-1952 (Box-folder 1 / 27)
    - Ismay Light and Telephone Company, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 1 / 28)
    - Kootenai Light and Power Company (Troy), 1928-1943 (Box-folder 1 / 29)
    - Lincoln Electric Cooperative (Eureka), 1954 (Box-folder 1 / 29)
    - Montana-Dakota Power Company, 1925-1933 (Box-folder 2 / 1-3)
    - Montana-Dakota Utilities Company (some are copies of reports to Federal Power Commission), 1936-1969 (Box-folder 2 / 4-9)
    - Montana Light and Power Company (Libby and Troy), 1930-1966 (Box-folder 2 / 10-11)
    - Montana Power Company (1930-1937 reports include subsidiaries Montana Reservoir and Irrigation Company; Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company; Great Falls Townsite Company; Rocky Mountain Power Company), 1914, 1936-1967 (Box-folder 2 / 12-18)
    - Mountain States Power Company (Baker, Elk Basin and Frannie Oil Fields, Forsyth, Kalispell, Libby, et al.; succeeded by Pacific Power and Light), 1929-1955 (Box-folder 3 / 1-10)
    - Neihart Water Company / Neihart Water and Light Company, 1914-1951 (Box-folder 3 / 11-12)
    - Neihart Water Company / Neihart Water and Light Company, 1914-1951 (Box-folder 3 / 11-12)
    - Opheim Electric Company (sold to Northern Electric Co-op Inc.), 1939-1945 (Box-folder 3 / 13)
    - Pacific Power and Light Company, 1913-1936 (Box-folder 3 / 14-17)
    - Pioneer Garage / Pioneer Electric Company (Jordan; sold to McCone County Electric Cooperative), 1939-1945 (Box-folder 3 / 18)
    - Plains Light and Water Company, 1913-1936 (Box-folder 3 / 19-20)
    - Plentywood Electric Company, 1922-1925 (Box-folder 4 / 1)
    - Pony-Harrison Light Company / Pony Electric Light Company, 1928-1952 (Box-folder 4 / 2)
    - Rexford Power and Light Company (sold to Rural Electric Administration), 1925-1950 (Box-folder 4 / 3-4)
    - Richey Electric (sold to McCone County Electric Cooperative), 1934-1945 (Box-folder 4 / 5)
    - Saltese Electric Light and Water Company / Saltese Electric and Water Works (sold to Montana Power Company), 1922-1946 (Box-folder 4 / 6-7)
    - Shelby Light Plant (sold to Great Northern Utilities Company), 1920-1921 (Box-folder 4 / 8)
    - Sunburst Light Company (sold to Great Northern Utilities Company), 1925-1926 (Box-folder 4 / 9)
    - Superior Electric Light and Water Works (sold to Montana Power Company), 1915-1950 (Box-folder 4 / 10-11)
    - Sweetgrass Electric Company / Sweetgrass Light, Heat, and Power Company (sold to Great Northern Utilities Company), 1925-1927 (Box-folder 4 / 12)
    - Thompson Falls Power Company (owned by Montana Power Company), 1914 (Box-folder 4 / 13)
    - Tobacco River Power Company (formerly Eureka Electric Company; sold to Lincoln Electric Cooperative), 1927-1952 (Box-folder 4 / 14-15)
    - Turner Electric Company (formerly Eureka Electric Company; sold to Lincoln Electric Cooperative), 1940-1946 (Box-folder 4 / 16)
    - Washington Water Power Company (only Montana operation was Noxon Dam; reports are copies of report to Federal Power Commission), 1957-1967 (Box-folder 4 / 17-22)
    - Westby Garage, 1922-1945 (Box-folder 4 / 23-24)
    - Wheeler Power and Light Company (sold to Rural Electric Administration, Glasgow), 1935-1948 (Box-folder 4 / 25)
    - White Water Motor Company (sold to Big Flat Electric Cooperative), 1947 (Box-folder 4 / 26)
    - Whitlash Refining Company (sold to Montana-Dakota Utilities Company), 1948 (Box-folder 4 / 27)
    - Winifred Light, Heat and Power Company (sold to Fergus County Electric Cooperative), 1940-1945 (Box-folder 4 / 28)
    - Rural electric cooperatives: A-Y (rate schedules only; they were not required to file annual reports), 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 4 / 29-31)
  - Appraisal Reports
    - Libby Light and Water Company, 1921 (Box-folder 4a / 1)
    - Miles City Electric Department, 1924 (Box-folder 4a / 2)
    - Mission Range Power Company, 1919 (Box-folder 4a / 3)
    - Mission Range Power Company and Flathead Valley Electric Company, 1927 (Box-folder 4a / 4)
  - Accident Reports, These records do not include minor non-utility related accidents such as car accidents, tripping, lifting, etc.
    - Montana-Dakota Utilities Company, 1957-1966, 1986 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
    - Montana Power Company, 1956-1966, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 5 / 2)
    - Pacific Power and Light Company, 1956-1966, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5 / 3)
- Gas Utility Companies, 1922-1967
  - Annual Reports
    - Bartlett Gas Company (Bartletsville; rate schedule only), 1928 (Box-folder 5 / 4)
    - Big Horn Oil and Gas Development Company (Hardin), 1928-1949 (Box-folder 5 / 5-7)
    - Billings Gas Company, 1927-1951 (Box-folder 5 / 8-10)
    - Blue Flame Oil Company (Kevin), 1926 (Box-folder 5 / 11)
    - Bowdoin Utilities Company, 1930-1934 (Box-folder 5 / 12)
    - Chinook Gas Company, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 5 / 13)
    - Citizens Gas Company (Shelby), 1928-1938 (Box-folder 5 / 14)
    - Consumers Gas Company (Sunburst, Ferdig, Oilmont, Sweetgrass), 1925-1967 (Box-folder 5 / 15-19)
    - Cut Bank Gas Utilities / Cut Bank Gas Company, 1930-1967 (Box-folder 6 / 1-4)
    - Drumheller Field Gas Service (Cut Bank), 1933-1941 (Box-folder 6 / 5)
    - Glendive Gas Utility (no report, just notes), 1927 (Box-folder 6 / 6)
    - Great Falls Gas Company, 1931-1967 (Box-folder 6 / 7-11)
    - Great Northern Utilities Company (Shelby; sold to Marias River Electric Cooperative), 1923-1946 (Box-folder 6 / 12-14)
    - Havre Natural Gas Company, 1929 (Box-folder 6 / 15)
    - Hungerford and Frazer (Oilmont; sold to Consumers Gas Company), 1927-1929 (Box-folder 6 / 16)
    - K. S. Huso (Ferdig; sold to Consumers Gas Company), 1930-1933 (Box-folder 6 / 17)
    - Kevin Gas Distributing Company, 1938-1967 (Box-folder 7 / 1-3)
    - Marias River Electric Cooperative (their gas department, Shelby), 1947-1951 (Box-folder 7 / 4)
    - Missoula Gas and Coke Company, 1930-1939 (Box-folder 7 / 5)
    - Montana-Dakota Power Company (Miles City, Glendive, Terry), 1930-1939 (Box-folder 7 / 6-7)
    - Montana-Dakota Utilities Company (Baker, Choteau, Conrad, Valier, Glasgow, Malta, Saco, Havre, et al.), 1935-1967 (Box-folder 7 / 8-13)
    - Montana Petroleum Company (Baker; sold to Montana-Dakota Utilities Company), 1925-1934 (Box-folder 7 / 14)
    - Montana Power Company, 1928-1967 (Box-folder 8 / 1-5)
    - Montana Utilities Service Company (Glasgow, Malta; rate schedule only), 1930 (Box-folder 8 / 6)
    - Northern Gas Company (Kevin; sold to Kevin Gas Distributing Company), 1926-1937 (Box-folder 8 / 7)
    - Northwest States Utilities Company (Conrad, Choteau, Valier, Havre, Chinook, Gallup City), 1930-1934 (Box-folder 8 / 8)
    - Pondera Utilities Company (Conrad, Choteau, Valier, Gallup City; becomes Northwest States Utilities Company), 1929-1930 (Box-folder 8 / 9)
    - Saco-Montana Gas Company, 1930 (Box-folder 8 / 10)
    - Saco Municipal Gas Service, 1937-1967 (Box-folder 8 / 11-14)
    - Shelby Gas Association (formerly Marias River Electric Cooperative), 1951-1967 (Box-folder 8 / 15-16)
    - H. O. Simmons (Conrad; rate schedule only), 1928 (Box-folder 8 / 17)
    - Thompson-Able Oil and Gas Company (Oilmont), 1933 (Box-folder 8 / 18)
  - Accident Reports, These records do not include minor non-utility related accidents such as car accidents, tripping, lifting, etc.
    - Montana-Dakota Utilities Company, 1957-1966 (Box-folder 8 / 19)
    - Montana Power Company, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 8 / 20)
- Heating Utility Companies, 1913-1961
  - Annual Reports
    - Mutual Heating Company / Billings Utility Company / Billings Gas Company, 1914-1918, 1933-1938 (Box-folder 9 / 1)
    - Butte Steam Heating Department of Montana Power Company, 1929-1950 (Box-folder 9 / 2)
    - Central Heating Company (Kalispell), 1950-1959 (Box-folder 9 / 3)
    - Havre Steam Heating Department of Montana Power Company, 1913-1919 (Box-folder 9 / 4)
    - Miles City Electric Heat and Power Department (rate schedules only), 1920-1927 (Box-folder 9 / 5)
    - Miles Land and Investment Company (Livingston), 1945-1960 (Box-folder 9 / 6)
    - Minnesota Northern Power Company (Miles City; rate schedules only), 1920-1927 (Box-folder 9 / 7)
    - Missoula Steam Heating Department of Montana Power Company, 1929-1960 (Box-folder 9 / 8-9)
    - Montana-Dakota Utilities Company (Glendive), 1928-1957 (Box-folder 9 / 10-11)
    - Montana-Dakota Utilities Company (Miles City), 1935-1961 (Box-folder 9 / 12-13)
    - Mountain States Power Company (Forsyth), 1930-1939 (Box-folder 9 / 14)
    - Valley Mercantile Corporation (Hamilton), 1929-1934 (Box-folder 9 / 15)
- Water Utilities, 1916-1969
  - Annual Reports
    - Alberton Water Company (includes rate schedule, 1922-1934), 1939-1946 (Box-folder 10 / 1)
    - Alberton City Water Works, 1947-1966 (Box-folder 10 / 2)
    - Anaconda Copper Mining Company. Waterworks Department, 1939-1954 (Box-folder 10 / 3)
    - Anaconda Company. Waterworks Department, 1955-1966 (Box-folder 10 / 4)
    - Anaconda: Butte Water Company. Anaconda Waterworks Division, 1939-1954 (Box-folder 10 / 5)
    - Baker, City of, Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1922), 1924, 1937-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 6)
    - Basin Water Company (includes rate schedule, 1941), 1941-1978 (Box-folder 10 / 7-8)
    - Bear Creek: S. and F. Water Works; Favero Water Works (includes rate schedule, 1916), 1939-1964 (Box-folder 10 / 9)
    - Bear Creek Municipal Water System, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 10)
    - Belgrade Water Works (includes rate schedule, 1916, 1926), 1940-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 11)
    - Bell Creek Utility Company, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 12)
    - Belt Municipal Waterworks (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1940-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 13)
    - Big Fork: Mountain States Power Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1954 (Box-folder 10 / 14)
    - Big Fork: Pacific Power and Light Company, 1958-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 15)
    - Big Fork: Red Gate Inc. Water Division, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 16)
    - Big Sandy, Town of, Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 17)
    - Big Timber Water Works (includes rate schedule, 1916), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 18)
    - Billings City Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1916-1954), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 10 / 19-21)
    - Billings Heights: county water district, 1965-1978 (Box-folder 10 / 22-23)
    - Black Eagle: Little Chicago Water Company, 1939-1978 (Box-folder 11 / 1-4)
    - Boulder Water Department, 1954-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 5)
    - Bozeman City Water Works (includes rate schedule, 1926-1948), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 6-8)
    - Bridger Water Department, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 9)
    - Broadus Water Department, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 10)
    - Broadview Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1916), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 11)
    - Brockton Water Department, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 12)
    - Browning Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1960 (Box-folder 11 / 13)
    - Butte Water Company (includes rate schedule, 1916-1935), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 14-17)
    - Cascade, Town of (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 18)
    - Charlo: Lake County Dairymen's Association (includes rate schedule, 1941), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 11 / 19)
    - Chester, Town of, 1951-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 20)
    - Chinook, City of, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 21)
    - Choteau, City of, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 22)
    - Circle, Town of, 1952-1968 (Box-folder 11 / 23)
    - Clyde Park Water Works, 1939-1945, 1953-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 1)
    - Columbia Falls, City of (includes rate schedules, 1949), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 2)
    - Columbia Falls: Columbia Heights Water Company / Worrell Water Company, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 12 / 3)
    - Columbia Falls: J. A. Talbott Water Company (rate schedule only), 1916 (Box-folder 12 / 4)
    - Columbus Municipal Water Works (includes rate schedules, 1918, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 5)
    - Conrad City Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1917, 1924), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 6-7)
    - Cooke City: Hooser's Water Service / Cooke City Water Users Association, 1952-1953, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 12 / 8-9)
    - Culbertson Waterworks, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 10)
    - Cut Bank Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1916), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 11-12)
    - Darby Water System, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 13)
    - Deer Lodge City Water Department, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 14)
    - Deer Lodge: Citizens Water Company / South Deer Lodge Water Company / Commonwealth Public Service Company (rate schedules only), 1916-1930 (Box-folder 12 / 15)
    - Denton, Town of (includes rate schedules, 1919), 1941-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 16)
    - Dillon Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 17-18)
    - Dodson, Town of, 1940-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 19)
    - Dutton, Town of, 1956-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 20)
    - East Helena, City of (includes rate schedule, 1930), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 21)
    - Ekalaka, Town of, 1937-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 22)
    - Ennis, Town of, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 23)
    - Eureka, Town of (includes rate schedule, 1916), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 24)
    - Eureka: Midvale Water Supply, 1969 (Box-folder 12 / 25)
    - Fairfield, Town of (includes rate schedule, 1946), 1952-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 1)
    - Fairview City Water Department, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 2)
    - Flaxville Water Department, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 3)
    - Forsyth City Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1922, 1926), 1959-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 4)
    - Fort Benton, City of (includes rate schedules, 1926, 1933), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 5-6)
    - Fortine Water Company (includes rate schedule, 1924), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 7)
    - Froid Water Department, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 8)
    - Fromberg, Town of (includes rate schedule, 1922), 1925-1931, 1945-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 9)
    - Gardiner Electric Light and Water Company (includes rate schedule, 1920), 1939-1968 (Box-folder 13 / 10)
    - Gardiner Park County Water District, 1969 (Box-folder 13 / 11)
    - Geraldine, Town of, 1929, 1937-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 12)
    - Geyser Artesian Water Association District, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 13 / 13)
    - Geyser Rural Improvement District, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 14)
    - Glasgow, City of (includes rate schedule, 1919), 1941-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 15-16)
    - Glendive, City of (includes rate schedule, 1921), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 17-18)
    - Glendive: Forest Park Water Corp. / Dawson County Rural Improvement District, #24, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 19)
    - Glendive: Highland Park Development Association / Highland Park Utilities Association, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 20)
    - Great Falls Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1926, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 21-22)
    - Hamilton: Montana Power Company, Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1942 (Box-folder 14 / 1)
    - Hamilton: Valley Water Company, 1942-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 2)
    - Hardin City Water Department, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 3)
    - Harlem, City of (includes rate schedules, 1920, 1926), 1925-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 4)
    - Harlowton Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1921), 1926-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 5-6)
    - Havre Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1916-1948), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 7-8)
    - Helena Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1935-1949, 1962), 1938-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 9-11)
    - Hingham: Hill County Water District (also serves Kremlin), 1969 (Box-folder 14 / 12)
    - Hinsdale Light and Water / Water and Sewer / Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1920, 1926), 1941-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 13)
    - Hot Springs Municipal Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1935), 1941-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 14)
    - Hungry Horse Water Company, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 15)
    - Hungry Horse: Glacier Water Company, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 16)
    - Hunntley Water Association Company, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 14 / 17)
    - Hysham, Town of (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1940-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 18)
    - Joliet, Town of (includes rate schedules, 1923, 1926), 1940-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 19-20)
    - Jordan Water System, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 14 / 21)
    - Judith Gap Water Department, 1924-1969 (Box-folder 15 / 1)
    - Kalispell Water Works Department (includes rate schedules, 1917, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 15 / 2-3)
    - Kalispell: Green Acres Water Association (articles of incorporation and bylaws, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 15 / 4)
    - Kalispell: Sunset Development Company, 1959-1983 (Box-folder 15 / 5-6)
    - Kevin, Town of, 1934-1938, 1944-1969 (Box-folder 15 / 7)
    - Keystone: Wilson and McHeffey, 1927-1941 (Box-folder 15 / 8)
    - Laurel Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1921, 1926, 1931), 1925-1969 (Box-folder 15 / 9-10)
    - Lewistown Water Works, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 15 / 11-12)
    - Libby: Mountain States Power Company (includes rate schedules, 1916, 1954), 1939-1954 (Box-folder 15 / 13-14)
    - Libby: Pacific Power and Light Company (includes rate schedules, 1956-1964), 1954-1969 (Box-folder 15 / 15-16)
    - Lima, Town of (includes rate schedule, 1922), 1924-1969 (Box-folder 15 / 17)
    - Livingston Municipal Water Works, 1939-1957 (Box-folder 15 / 18-19)
    - Livingston Municipal Water Works (includes rate schedules, 1919, 1926), 1958-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 1)
    - Lodge Grass Water Department, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 2)
    - Malta Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 3)
    - Manhattan Water Works, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 4)
    - Martin City Water Company, 1948, 1952-1979 (Box-folder 16 / 5-6)
    - Marysville: Beuschlein Water Works, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 16 / 7)
    - Medicine Lake Water Works (includes rate schedules, 1916, 1926), 1940-1955, 1958, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 8)
    - Melstone Water Department, 1920-1926, 1931-1938, 1942-1968 (Box-folder 16 / 9)
    - Miles City Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1916, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 10-11)
    - Milltown: Matt Lehti / Aileen Lehti Anderson (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 12)
    - Missoula: Farviews Development Company, 1952-1967 (Box-folder 16 / 13)
    - Missoula Water Department of Montana Power Company (includes Superior from 1952-1960; rate schedule, 1916), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 14-16)
    - Moore Municipal Water Works (includes rate schedules, 1916, 1926), 1938-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 17)
    - Musselshell Water Works (also named Musselshell Rural Special Improvement District), 1925-1931, 1936, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 16 / 18)
    - Musselshell Water Company (also named New Water System), 1962-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 19)
    - Nashua Water Department, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 20)
    - Neihart Water and Light Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1938-1951 (Box-folder 16 / 21)